Thomas Seropian

French & Lebanese dual nationalities Currently based in London, United Kingdom Phone: +44 74 2362 9937 E-mail: thomas@seropian.io https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tseropian

Technology Manager / Chief Technologist

Skillset

Media development, innovation, start-ups, ICT4D, entrepreneurship, freedom of expression, closed states Leadership, communication with technical and non-technical audiences.

Team recruitment and management. Agile delivery. Business and technical development.

Strong sense of innovation. Creativity and flexibility.

Design and user stories. Research, prototyping. Group training and capacity building.

Establishment and management of a team of 4 technologists in London for an international NGO.

Project management. International partnerships coordination.

Architecture, design and implementation new generation applications. Digital Security

Work experience

Technology manager for an international NGO

Internews London, United Kingdom – 2015 – present (www.internews.org)

ightarrow Managing Human Rights technology team and activities across multiple countries

Leading the design, development and delivery a portfolio of innovation and technology activities supporting local media ecosystems among the most repressive regimes. Managing and monitoring activities' budgets. Ensuring the technology infrastructure meets our beneficiaries' needs. Designing rapid response to urgent needs for support from partners in the field. Responsible for technical architecture and back-end infrastructure for the whole project.

Overseeing recruitment and managing a team of 4 technologists. Ensuring planning, coordination and distribution of work, setting priorities, agreeing detailed work plans, budgets and schedules. Coaching and mentoring team members, performance management.

→ Strategic Development and Learning

Leading the design and implementation of policies and guidelines for technologies activities

Conceptualizing and design of innovative approaches for using technology in closed countries. Participating to fund-raising. Representing at conferences and events.

Proposal planning. Improving quality of development processes (including specification, operations, testing, deployment, policy writing...);

Freelance consultant in open source technologies
Self Employed London, United Kingdom 2014-2015 (www.seropian.io)

- → Designing & developing web applications and prototypes for various range of clients
- \rightarrow Areas of work: E-Commerce, ERP web applications, Infrastructure management.

Designed and built a subscription based application, including automated online payments for a start-ups incubator. Iterative Prototyping of CRM and back office applications

Developed web based Intranet including import/export modules for a travel booking agent.

Defined and prioritized user stories in close collaboration with different team members.

Implemented a Git driven process for development and deployment for the application.

→ Training and mentoring on digital security, online privacy and cryptography

Trained Digital Security and online privacy to journalists and European institutions members.

ICT Projects manager / Web application engineer for an international NGO Internews Europe Paris, France / London, United Kingdom 2009-2013 (www.internews.eu)

→ On-line freedom of expression, support of local media, digital security

Designing, developing & supporting multilingual web applications

Writing user stories & specifications during inception. Managing external contractors and developer.

Developing and maintaining custom modules. Integration with third party providers APIs.

Writing documentation for users. Managing localizations, training & support with teams.

Managing technical resources & back-office infrastructures.

Managing back-offices for ICT activities: web platforms, secure hosting & video platforms. Deploying and monitoring cloud based infrastructure.

Building, delivering and facilitating trainings & trainers on ICT topics

Training of trainers on website building and digital security (West Africa, MENA, Europe)

Software engineer for a social networking service designed for a family use **Hellotipi.com** Paris, France 2008 (www.hellotipi.com)

 \rightarrow Designed, developed and implemented new features for the service.

Video sharing. Photo tagging. Revamped registration process. Multilingual support & more.

Managed client support, designed tutorials, wrote blog posts.

ICT projects manager for a local NGO in Armenia

Fondation KASA Yerevan, Armenia 2006-2007 (www.kasa.am)

Coordinated Computer trainings in youth training centres.

Developed activities in 2 major cities.

Managed recruitment of local team. Provided technical support for training & social programs. Participated to feasibility studies & design for countrywide projects.

Assistant manager for e-training IT projects for an international training centre **Valeo Thermal Systems** Paris, France 2005 (www.valeo.com)

Designed & implemented tools for course supports creation (virtual classes, e-learning modules).

Technology stack

OO PHP (MVC), Drupal, Javascript, HTML5, Bootstrap, SASS, RESTful APIs, AWS (EC2, S3, Cloudfront, Route53, IAM), MySQL, jQuery, Linux, Apache, Nginx, Solr, GIT, SVN, JSON, XML, Selenium

Education

MSc in Computer Sciences and Innovation

Ecole Supérieure d'Informatique, Electronique, Automatique Paris, France

5 years engineering school in information technologies & electronics (www.esiea.fr).

 \rightarrow Graduated with first class honours.

Foreign languages

French: Mother tongue English: Fluent Spanish: Basic level Arabic: Beginner